tagline for my company [music] is
humanizing AI for care. We've talked
about how healthcare needs to be
emotionally ready before it can be
technologically ready. [music]
Help people feel safe, seen, and
empowered as that change happens.
latchment on something which is already
there and bend on that
>> and hundreds of thousands of dollars on
the data that powers the technology.
>> Uh.com revolution internet and now AI I
think it's the I think AI is the is the
[music] quickest technology I mean human
species have ever adapted like in the
shortest frame of time. One of the major
components of AI first approach is PPD
people, processes and tools. So people
is the first step.
Welcome to all of our listeners to the
Singer Room podcast. We're on location
at Planet Hollywood in Las Vegas. This
morning I have the privilege of
discussing all things AI and some pretty
pretty cool technologies that that my my
new friend Parth has been working on.
Parth, welcome to the second room.
Thanks for being with us.
>> Thanks for having me here. Of course,
>> we've been hearing about so many
different aspects of AI and it it's so
exciting. I mean, I don't know about
you, but I feel like I found my people.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh this is really just a lot a lot of
fun and and but there's so much good
that people are are involved with here
and I I just feel like we're just
scratching the surface of the
opportunities we're going to find to to
do things together. Um, what I want to
kind of jump into, so I know that you're
you've got a company that's really doing
some interesting things because you have
an interesting background as well. U
we're thinking about, you know, building
AI that that it really is it's ethical.
Um, it hopefully augments and supports
humans. It's not really going to replace
it, but but you know, people can debate
that all all they want to, and I don't
think that's going to get solved anytime
soon. So love to hear a little bit about
your your background. I know you've done
some interesting things even before
NetSmarts, but uh love to hear about you
know what you're passionate about and
what led you to where you are today in
launching your company and some some of
the fun things that you're doing.
>> Absolutely. You know, thank you so much.
Uh I think uh yeah to your point it's a
it's a really interesting world we are
living in and uh you know we are lucky
to kind of see a lot of transitions
during our lifetime, right? I mean
uh.com revolution internet and now AI I
think it's the I think AI is the is the
quickest technology I mean human species
have ever adapted like in the shortest
frame of time right and it's so
fascinating uh you know uh I was
discussing with some of the colleagues
and even with you uh you know that it's
all those sci-fi movies coming you know
into reality in in some way or the other
right so yeah so about myself um I have
been uh involved in you know digital
transformation automation custom
software development space that's how I
started my career 20 years back and um I
have been involved in the world of SAS
primarily and that is uh you know that
is something uh you know we as an
organization and I as an individual we
hold a very strong expertise on and
something we are really proud of that we
have created multiple SAS products I
mean in fact thousands of them for our
clients over last two decades and then
um you know we got into the space of AI
since uh 2016 it's been fairly
10-year-old AI practice test we built at
Netsmarts and you know similarly I have
been in the world of AI since then and
uh we started with small projects like
you know data labeling projects which
which were you know common back in the
days because AI thrives on data as we
all know right and you know we were
creating a large data set for
organizations who could you know then go
with the AIdriven approach and that's
how we started into this segment but
yeah I mean um so my focus really
revolves around uh creating uh you know
AI first strategies for organizations
who are looking either to step into the
AI world and trying to decode what would
work for them, what would not work for
them rather than just you know investing
AI into AI you know just for the heck of
it and look cool around it right so
actually driving business use cases
which can get them some ROIs in shorter
or long term right and uh you know
helping them craft out their AI first
road map that you know because every
organization is unique in their own ways
yes
>> right and not one shoe is going to fit
all Right.
>> So, so yeah, that's that's what we are
really passionate about and that is what
you know we are working towards.
>> Well, you you're you're touching on
something that's actually what my the
whole premise of this this show is
about. It's like there's so much noise
that people are claiming all they're
doing all these wonderful things with
AI, but through the noise there's
there's a signal that we have to dial in
on and what you do is actually precisely
that. And so tell me how has the EU
approached kind of separating hype from
reality and identifying the the real
world use cases that are meaningful not
just you know somebody's excited because
they can chat GPT and it you know it
basically accelerates what Google used
to do in a millisecond in Google search.
Yeah, absolutely. I think uh I have
always believed in the fact that big
wins lie in small things probably,
right? It's not necessary that you have
to make a AI use case which is really
out of the box and then you're like you
know you've done something big. It could
be as small as automating one of your
department functions where it might not
be contributing in form of direct
revenues but maybe contributing towards
increasing your uh employees
efficiencies or you know you
accelerating your go to market in some
way or the other or for your clients
right and it doesn't have to be uh you
know rocket science around it right so
to give you an example uh you know we we
are one of our use cases which we're
really proud of is in the customer
support and customer experience side of
things, right? Every organization needs
better customer support as they keep
growing because you know uh
organizations they grow based on
retention of clients. That is how you
know we have believed and we have grown
as well as an organization and that that
is I think is is an industry agnostic
use case. I mean every business needs
that right. So in one of the use cases
we kind of automated the L1 level of uh
ticketing in terms of customer support.
So AI actually handles the L1 in form of
chat as well as in form of voice. Right?
So now imagine that AI is able to take
let's say that you get 1,000 customer
support queries every day, right? And
I'm taking a very minimal number. It
goes way beyond that in some businesses,
right? And then you know you're out of
which 50% is also handled by AI for
example. And then 50% is handed off by
AI to a human agent where it is not able
to convince the customer with the
resolution. And then of course you are
improving on the efficiency because out
of those 50% you know eventually AI is
going to take another 25% gradually
because it's going to learn right. So
now you know you are slowly and steadily
automating your customer support
functions increasing the bandwidth of
your uh you know regular human customer
support agents. And then they can do
meaningful work for their customers and
move them towards customer success
roadmap because there's a very thin line
between support and success for
especially for growing organizations.
Right.
>> Right. And they're not able to focus on
success because they are most of the
times they're dialing their time in the
sport. Right. So very small use case but
then big time impact. Right. So it it's
all about what would work for you, what
your business needs.
>> Yeah. And I think the what I find
interesting is we're in this place in
time where trust has been eroded
massively in every part of society and
people are terrified. There's a this
fear factor and you know what you're
talking about is identifying meaningful
workflows that are actually close to
where the action is. Um there's
something there's a cultural aspect to
to really getting the engagement that
you need to have people raise their hand
and say hey look this is a workflow that
I think we could actually make it a lot
better. uh ho how of do you see that and
what what what's what's your thought
about what leadership needs to be doing
inside of organizations to foster a
culture that people feel safe to
actually identify those things if they
don't feel safe that some of the biggest
impact things cuz you mentioned some
little things people might not bring it
up for fear of losing their job to AI
>> yeah 100% I think I think the fear is
real and u and it's something which I
would not say is wrong, right? Because
uh let's be honest, I mean some roles
are going to vanish 100%. Right? But I
also believe that this is not the first
transition we are going through and this
is not the last one as well. Right? We
have we have lived through similar
transitions in the past. I mean of
course not as massive as AI probably but
but we have we have gone through that
and the only thing which I think uh has
made us all survive is the ability to
adapt right and then upscale because uh
and I think every organization or top
leadership should really promote
upskilling and then you know should make
their uh you know their team members
feel safe that okay you know this is
your road map and that is where you know
we also come in with the AI force
approach and one of the major components
of AI first approach is PPT people,
processes and tools. So people is the
first step your your team needs to be
dialed in to the concept and it has to
the approach has to fall from top to the
bottom. It is not a bottom top approach,
right? So the top leadership has to
convince its people that this is the
road map we are going towards. Everyone
is safe provided you do XYZ things,
right? And then you upscale. So, you
need to prepare for the newer roles when
the older roles are actually going to
eventually move out of the market.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> That's right. Yeah. And for our
listeners,
you're you're hearing from a a CEO of a
tech company and they're telling you it
starts with people. Can't forget that.
I'm glad that you're saying it because
we are at this inflection point where
leadership has to be really walking a
fine line with the transparency has to
be important. Um we have to be careful
obviously with the timing of everything
that we're doing. Some things that you
know as an executive that uh that that
you you kind of have to work through and
figure out timing and how to to deliver
that and implement things in your
organization. But there's also this
really uh important piece about trust
being eroded.
We have to find a way to help people to
be comfortable that we're we're working
with them. We're not trying to do
something to them. We're trying to find
ways to enable them. And you said yes,
jobs are going to be replaced. I think
you're right. But I think the the
message we want to make sure people are
hearing is
it's going to replace people who don't
adopt and learn how to use AI. And so
executives really need to hear from you
the things that you're you're talking
about. People is the very first thing on
the list.
>> Yes.
>> Um what are some of the barriers that
you see and and what would you tell um
executives that that may be listening?
They're trying to figure out where's
that fine line because they don't have
the understanding of AI that you have
and they might be a bit a little bit u
nervous. I mean apart from reaching out
and getting having a conversation with
you, what are some of the things you
would advise them to be thinking about
and doing?
>> I think uh whenever there's a there's a
transition phase uh it's uh is a fear
which actually kicks in first and it it
can it kind of could kick in in the top
leadership as well and as well as in
your midline managers. I think it's very
important as a CEO or as a seale uh
executive in an organization you need to
convince your midline managers first
right that okay you know this is what we
are following because they are the one
who are hustling on the ground level
every day right and they need to manage
the entire workforce which is going to
be working towards your AI first
strategy or whatever you opt in terms of
AI implementation in your business right
so have certain designated you know AI
officers inside the organization who
lead initiatives because you establish
lish trust with them at the first place
that they are like they need to be in a
good place they need to feel that okay
I'm a part of this right and and
whatever the board is deciding I am very
much involved and I'm an equal
stakeholder in this so that they can
give the same comfort to their downline
>> yes
>> right and then a clear road map is very
important you know make small wins uh
visible right have small goals maybe
next 6 months we are going to automate
your our outreach function maybe our
sales outreach Right? And then you have
the sales managers kind of you know
working towards that and maybe
implementation of tools and everything
but you can implement all the tools out
there in the world unless and until it
is not processized and your people are
not using it. It's it's it's a cash burn
right. So so you know a whole systematic
approach and sometimes what we do is
that we tend to do things ourselves and
you know that is where we lose the
battle. I I strongly encourage that you
know uh it's not necessary that
everything has to be done inhouse. get
get experts you know to help you.
There's a reason why there are experts,
right? I mean, we are a techdriven
organization and if tomorrow, you know,
someone comes and uh talks to me about
manufacturing uh you know uh and set up
a manufacturing plant, I'm not the
expert in that. I would rather go to
someone who has actually been there,
done it, right? And who accelerates my,
you know, uh uh uh my time to market,
right? rather than me trying to hustle
things and then you know I I I lose time
and as well as I lose money and then you
know then I realize oh my god you know I
should have got a specialist in on
board. So I think it's very important
you know get get an expert speed up have
a road map and then maybe you take
things back in house and in control
>> right no I think that makes a lot of
sense I think
you're really talking about some things
that I think people have to really
open up their their thinking a little
bit um cuz culture gets talked about in
in ways that
honestly sometimes don't it it feels
almost like an exercise and you're
checking a box but in reality
It takes commitment, repetition, and to
use your your words, you have to have a
systemic approach to this. And so, you
know, getting to them your mid-level
managers, the people who are closest to
the workforce that are really doing
these these critical jobs.
If an organization is is trying to
figure out
where to start and and put the put the
pieces together so that the you're
starting to repair some of the trust
things because roughly about 20 years
ago, um, eight out of 10 people would
have told you that they trust the
government.
probably higher percentage trust their
their clergy, their law enforcement. Um,
you know, pick an entity, but even for
CEOs in particular now, the number is in
the low 20s that 20 I think it's like
24% of what I heard recently.
How would you advise CEOs to engage
their their next level management in
order to start rebuilding that culture
so that there's trust and they're able
to move advanced things forward because
to your point it's it'smemes the subject
matter experts that actually be able to
point out the areas of opportunity and
if they're afraid and they don't trust
how are you going to get them to
actually step forward and help? Yeah, I
think it starts with uh empowerment
first, right? Your your managers, your
midline, they needs to feel empowered
and they need to, you know, to what I
was saying uh you know it they need to
feel that they're they're stakeholders
in this journey overall somehow, right?
Because with with that feeling comes a
lot of ownership, right? and then they
will work with you with your vision
because your vision becomes their
vision. It is it is very important to
translate your vision in very clear
actionable items and then you know tell
them what they have to gain in this win
right it's uh I mean yesterday at one of
the roundts I was speaking the same
thing I was like there is no deal where
there is not a win-win situation if it's
if it's a one-sided win I mean even in
in in our normal relationships right I
mean you cannot carry a relationship
longer if it's if it's only one person
who is winning there has to be some kind
of ratio. So I mean even if it's like
7030 and then it kind of changes
eventually and you know it it goes a
little up and down but there has to be a
win for the other side of the table as
well right so so for your midline
managers it is very important they see
that what is the win there for them
because at the end of the day everyone
is here to do something in their life
they're ambitious and that's why they're
working most of them I would say right
so um and then the kind of uh uh you
know drift we are we are witnessing
right now in the overall technology
everything is changing so rapidly every
day there's new development there are
new algorithms which are getting you
know developed and the whole working
norm is changing across different
industries and there's no way out of it
I mean it's inevitable this change is we
are supposed to go through it there's
there's nothing there's there's no way
we can we have a way out of it it's just
that we have to adapt to it and everyone
knows that deep inside know with fear
too but that's okay it's okay to have
fear but what is important is that how
you are uh facing that fear and what
steps are you forming to get there
>> right yeah it it's a
it's an old concept that we've been
dealing with since the dawn of mankind
disruptive innovation is real and and it
happens and you know if we think back
through the dot transition
I I know that a lot of us never never
could have imagined how things would
turn out and how how much the internet
connectivity has transformed pretty much
every part of our lives, you know, in
the civilized world, industrialized
world anyways. Um, this I think who
knows, I don't know if it's 10x or a
thousandx or whatever it is, but we know
it's it's massively disruptive and we
it's only that consistent communication
with human beings and really doing
things deliberately to establish a safe
environment for people where they do
they actually feel like they're
contributing. They can they're able to
drive some things and take ownership of
it. Um I think I was speaking with
somebody yesterday and at least put it
in a really simple term for me. You have
to have these conversations and answer
the question that they have in their
mind. What's in this for me? I mean, if
I go and do these things, what's what's
in it for me? Cuz you know, you're I
think you you'd want me to help help you
eliminate my job.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Apple and and then
everything does not have to be innovated
from ground level, right? I mean take
example of the touchscreen phones. I
mean Apple came came out with them
first. I mean Blackberry was drooling at
one point of time. The only small tweak
what they did was they got rid of the
keyboards. And it wasn't that we were
not operating on screens without
keywords from before. I mean your your
your laptop or even your desktop. I mean
you were using a mouse but you were
actually on a screen. You were not you
know doing everything from the keyboard.
So they just used that concept and got
rid of the real estate and made a larger
screen. And today we we are living on on
a you know on a smartphone day in day
out with with a complete touchscreen
panel. So it's not that you do
everything from ground up. Maybe you you
take something maybe you know there's so
many LLMs out there. There are so many
models out there. there are open source
models out there right you know plug and
play and then make something which is
you know you're solving a real problem
rather than just saying that hey I'm
doing AI because I meet a lot of people
these days and you know in a very uh
lighter manner I always say that AI
organizations are just breeding like
mushrooms right everyone is doing AI
right but are you solving a real problem
is the question yes because that is what
is required for longevity of your
organization so you have to be dealing
dealing with real problems and you're
giving real solutions.
>> Yeah. The the days of uh getting
sneaking by with with understanding of
buzzwords, the the game's kind of up now
because you you can't do a whole lot of
uh implementations of AI without getting
an ROI uh because it's not inexpensive
to do these things. It just isn't. So
yeah, it it's a very exciting but a
maybe a little intimidating sometimes
when when they think about what
replicants because I don't even think we
know um like to your point everything's
moving so quickly.
Six or eight months ago I remember
trying to get an image created using AI
and it was it giving me these really
horrendous things. I have no artistic
talent when it comes to drawing but I
could do better than it was doing just
that long ago. I have nothing related to
drawing as well.
>> But now I mean it's incredible what it
can do. It creates things. I mean I I if
you can imagine it you could probably
get something that looks close to it and
it looks like it was done like with our
imprecision.
I I don't know how but it it is amazing
how fast it's gone.
>> Yeah. And we all have that advisor you
know working with us which is called
Chad GPT or co-pilot right. and gets us
all the clinical information, data,
stats and everything. So if you really
want to do something and you know make
solutions I think we are living in a
perfect era it's just that we need to
you know use it in the right direction
and then maybe you know like I said I
have an expert work with you right I
mean if if you want your child to become
a football player tomorrow you will not
tell him that hey you know what son
start watching YouTube videos and you
know you'll become um you know Ronaldo
one day right I mean you have to find
him the best soccer coach out there who
has been there done it who has created
players and then you help work on that.
So everything cannot be chat GPT or
YouTube or Google, right? I mean there
there there will always be a human
component always. You cannot leave
decision-m in the hands of AI. I mean
I'm strongly against that, right? But
you can use it for getting you
visibility and you know guiding you that
this could be possibilities but the
decision-m should always be with you.
>> Absolutely. I couldn't agree with you
more. Before we wrap, this has been a
fascinating conversation. First of all,
and and I I hope you'll you'll come back
and and and be on the show with me again
because there's so much more that we
could talk about and honestly in in a
couple months, I'll bet you you'll have
some late breaking news that'll be
really interesting for people to hear
about. I I know I'll be interested. Um,
but if if people wanted to get in touch
with you or they want to know how do I
find the the right experts to figure out
what's hype and what's reality where I
put my resources, how do people get in
touch with you?
>> So, you can find me on LinkedIn. I think
that's the easiest way to find me. Uh,
you know, just search Parth Gargish.
That's my name. Uh, it's quite unique. I
mean, I've not seen anyone with the same
name on the planet till now. Nowhere in
the social media. So, that works for me.
So you can find me on LinkedIn very
easily or you can you know you can reach
me on my email uh you know
part.garesh@netmarts.com
garagesmarts.com.
I also run a community for SAS business
owners called SAS next SAS NXT. So, uh
you know we we do events and shows
across North America and we are trying
to create a community, you know, where
SAS business owners can come in,
collaborate, innovate with each other,
right? Because I'm I'm a person who has
been very strong believer of
partnerships. I I mean even with our
even with our clients I mean we work
more like partners rather than vendors
because you know we we strongly believe
in that that uh our success lies in
their success you know if they're not
successful in the long term I will not
have a client for life and that is
something we're really proud of that we
have created clients for life right so
so and that is what helps you sail
through you know those rough days too
like the pandemic and everything right I
mean you survive through it as an
organization only if you have clients
who have believed with you and who are
working with you as partners right so so
yeah I I mean uh that is the idea that
why we created that community and you
know I'm really passionate about it. So
if in case you're a SAS business owner
please feel free to hit up and I would
love to kind of have you there as a as a
community member. Yeah,
>> that's fantastic. I just I love the
focus on people are people are first.
This is a it's so refreshing and I'm
excited about what you're doing. Can't
wait to to see hear about your
successes. Uh let's definitely keep in
touch and hope you enjoy the rest of the
time here. I know there's a lot of good
conversations being had and to your
point I think a lot of partnerships are
going to get born out of these few days
here in Las Vegas. So Park, it's been an
amazing pleasure to to have you. Thanks
so much for being on the show.
>> Well, thank you for having me here. It
was a lovely conversation. I would look
forward towards, you know, a longer
conversation sometime. Yeah.
>> Oh, let's do that. Yeah. Good luck.
Thank you.
>> That's it for this episode of the Signal
Room. If today's conversation sparks
something in you, an idea, a challenge,
or a perspective worth amplifying, I'd
love to hear from you. Message me on
LinkedIn or visit cigarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.